<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://Doria325.github.io</id>
    <title>Doria&apos;s Workshop</title>
    <updated>2025-12-26T07:34:12.417Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://Doria325.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://Doria325.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <logo>https://Doria325.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://Doria325.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2025, Doria&apos;s Workshop</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Project: Summer at UCLA]]></title>
        <id>https://Doria325.github.io/post/my-project-summer-at-ucla/</id>
        <link href="https://Doria325.github.io/post/my-project-summer-at-ucla/">
        </link>
        <updated>2025-12-23T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago, I had the opportunity of experiencing being a Bruin for three weeks, which is definitely one of the most special experiences I ever had. I was able to develop a more insightful understanding in architecture through the lectures, engaging with enthusiasts in this field and the process of building my first project. This article is a process journal that records my growth by working on this project and reflections I have.</p>
<h2 id="stage-1-initial-brainstorming">Stage 1: Initial Brainstorming</h2>
<p>The instructions received for working through the first stage was to create a model of any form we want by choosing at least 2 or more provided materials having dichotomies that produce contrasting effects. Examples include hard and soft textures, rigid and fluid states, industrial and artificial materials and more. Meant to attain quantity over quality, this stage was mainly intended for us to explore our creativity. Although instructors encouraged us not to focus too much on the requirements, I still felt constrained choosing dichotomies, materials and the form of my model because pictures of exquisite models shown during the orientation kept flashing in my mind.</p>
<p>Straw was the first material I picked, considering it as a familiar material common in my daily life and looking easier to manipulate. I started by cutting them into equal smaller pieces and experimented very randomly on how they can form a structure. Inspired by Hangzhou Sports Park Stadium (maybe because I watched too many concert videos), I arranged the straws in a wavy, circular form like a blooming flower using a combination of black and transparent straws. My goal was to show the dichotomy of fluid and rigid by using stiff material to create a shape that reveals softness and fluidity. It was until completing the first layer of transparent straws that I suddenly thought of attaching the second layer using black straws, thinking if I can make the structure “float.” Hence, I think the dichotomies of opaque and transparent now match more with my model.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766673975487.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Here is how my model looks like half-way completed</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Completing this first model immersed me into the mood of crafting a bit more, so the production of the next models went a bit more fluent. The goal of this stage was really about experimentation, so I tried to make models in very distinctive forms. Starting off was difficult for me, because I had always been used to completing tasks with specific requirements and instructions. Confronting creativity is not easy; it requires us to break through the cage we trapped ourselves with from fear of failure.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674133296.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Some more experimentations</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="stage-2-bringing-ideas-further">Stage 2: Bringing Ideas Further</h2>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674236336.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674243303.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Model 2.1</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is the model that I am most satisfied with. I see irregularity in it and the style of modernity. It reminds me of structures in sci-fi films–structures that require us to take a second and closer look to understand its form and how it was built. In this model, I like how subtle connections between pieces create an illusion as if some upper layers are floating by themselves. I identified it as a strength, which led me to my next steps of revision.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="5"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674346918.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Model 2.1</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="6"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674361219.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
</blockquote>
<p>In the second stage, we were informed that our architecture is designated to be placed in the courtyard of Perloff Hall, the UCLA architecture department building. Building on the strengths and my interests from Model 2.1, I wanted to emphasize the feature of suspension. Just like what I did in Model 1.1, the combination of black and transparent straws enhances this illusion. By using transparent straws, I tried to make some sections seem detached from each other and hover independently in the air, challenging viewers’ perception of gravity.</p>
<p>I inserted wood sticks through some straws to create alignments with the materials and the direction of the hallway poles of Perloff. In this way, I try to enhance the connection between my architecture and its environment.</p>
<p>Reflecting on myself and from peer feedback, I think my strength at this point was being able to identify the style and aesthetic features I want to present. Yet, I have also identified some flaws I want to fix. Moving into the finalizing stage, I want to clarify the functions of my architecture and think about how I can alter the form of my model to blend it well with Perloff.</p>
<h2 id="stage-3-breaking-through-the-cage">Stage 3: Breaking Through the Cage</h2>
<p>I try to list out some clashing elements that create the visual detachment between Model 2.2 and the environment.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="7"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674401989.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>A Simple Problem Analysis Chart</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Having problems identified more clearly, I decided to make adjustments to the material and shape. I gave up black straw, the material I have been sticking with all the way and replaced it with wood sticks. In this way, I altered the industrial style to a more natural one. But I still used the transparent straws to keep the detaching and floating illusion I discovered.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674539247.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>FInal Model Elevation View</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To blend it more with its environment, I also changed the interaction technique from alignment to extension. Instead of growing upwards in a cone-like shape, I built my final model with more horizontal expansion to fill the courtyard space and have some parts laid on the roof of the hallways. By doing so, I think the architecture looks like it’s grown from the Perloff building and it now has a tighter connection with its environment.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="8"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674546527.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Final Model Perspective View</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Coming to these changes was not simple. It took me days to arrive at the solution of changing the material because I was stuck with the black straws for nearly the entire process, too focused on it to the extent that I have forgotten about the other materials available. Once again, I trapped myself in a cage I built. Finding the way to break through can be simple but hard to spot.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766674744470.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Final Model Close View</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With the final design gradually taking shape and some environmental features clarified, it became somewhat natural for me to see its  function as a space like a garden for leisure and refreshment. I observed that a lot of students in the summer program often hang out in the courtyard during breaks, but there are limited sunshades that allow them to hide from the scorching sun in LA, especially at noon. Thus, I imagined it as a garden with shady tree shades that creates a space for refreshment and leisure. Building a more comprehensive understanding of the environment allows me to picture a clearer image for my architecture.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766675354932.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Final Model Elevation View</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="9"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766675127792.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Final Model Plan VIew</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="10"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766675149066.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Final Model Section View</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="reflecting-on-my-growth">Reflecting on My Growth</h2>
<p>Serving as my first try of being an “architect,” my experience at UCLA TeenArch Summer Program was novel, interesting but also challenging. I had to constantly apply critical thinking skills when arriving at each step to identify flaws, weaknesses and come up with solutions and ways to improve. The process also allowed me to realize the need of being observant to daily lives and my surrounding environment, as I am once again reminded, that the primary purpose of architecture is to serve the people.</p>
<p>I used to think of myself as an uncreative person, but going through this process helped me to find strategies to jump out of the box built by unnecessary rules I set for myself. For me, finding my creativity was the biggest obstacle I overcame and what brought me the hugest sense of accomplishment. Here is a quote that I really like from one of the presenters in my studio during our final review:<br>
<em>&quot;Design is not about getting right at once, but a process of letting ideas grow.&quot;</em></p>
<p>Lastly, thanks to my instructor, family and friends who helped and supported me through this journey! It was truly a memorable summer with you all here at LA:)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Some more Photos from UCLA:)</p>
</blockquote>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="11"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766675955166.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="12"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766675950081.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="13"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766675960373.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="14"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1766675966851.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[City Exploration: Shanghai–Looking Forward to the Past]]></title>
        <id>https://Doria325.github.io/post/shanghai-looking-forward-to-the-future/</id>
        <link href="https://Doria325.github.io/post/shanghai-looking-forward-to-the-future/">
        </link>
        <updated>2025-07-25T06:46:47.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Architecture preservation is defined by the process of restoring or maintaining buildings, structures and other physical elements of the built environment that holds significant historical or cultural means. But what is it that we are attempting to keep? Is it only limited to the spatial dimensions of places? Architecture preservation includes the historical narratives, values and culture behind the physical building. Through these old structures, we conserve a bridge that connects the present to the past by stories embedded in their walls that remind us of our collective past and unique identity. They shape the present community, and continue to inspire the future as symbols of resilience and endurance, reminding the shared values and history. However, under rapid modernization and urban expansion, should we lean to the past or look toward the future?</p>
<h2 id="what-i-see-in-shanghai">What I see in Shanghai</h2>
<p>Architecture preservation in Shanghai has gone through several stages. Policies evolved over time due to difficulties in identifying what to preserve. Shanghai is one of my favorite cities in China. Although I have been there numerous times, my curiosity towards this city never quite diminished. I like walking along The Bund in the evening. Looking to my left are the futuristic skyscrapers, including the Oriental Pearl Tower, Jin Mao Tower and Shanghai Tower, flashing glaring, colorful lights. On my right are the Custom House, China Merchant Bank–historic buildings constructed under western colonial influence. The Bund allows the past and the present of Shanghai to exist at the same time. Separated by river, stories of the eastern and western culture echo from the two shores. Yet, old stories beyond the neon lights are even more treasurable.</p>
<p>During my spring break in 2025, I went on another trip to Shanghai. I spent a day on a city walk, starting from Wukang Mansion, followed by Wukang Rd. all the way to Anfu Rd., crossed Wulumuqi (M) Rd. and arrived at Huaihai (M) Rd. On this route are iconic old Shanghai tree-lined streets guarded by sturdy, tall, century-old sycamore trees. The mottled barks and bare branches form a dense canopy, creating a tunnel effect, feeling like walking through a time travel tunnel that takes me back to the 1800s French Concession. Trees do not reveal a strong sense of historic and western culture atmosphere without the red and yellow-brick houses at the sides. Most of them are old houses preserved or refurbished from the last century.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1754290042978.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A Very Cool City Walk Map（Self, 2025)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My main purpose of walking along this route was to shop through the fancy clothing stores, boutiques, cafes, bakeries etc, but I noticed that some museums and historic sites were hidden behind the tall brick walls. Historic sites like the Former Residence of Ba Jin, Soong Ching-ling Memorial Residence are places I would not go specifically but I'd be glad to stop by and have a look. A lot of the old, western-style buildings were also renovated to be designated for commercial purposes, such as the House of Rong Family that was turned into Prada showroom after restoration. These places still remained as where they were–now turned into light commercial buildings and districts were like selections of a history book intersected in people’s daily lives.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1754416801606.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Anfu Rd, Shanghai (Self, 2025)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Another place that surprised me was the National Museum, the birthplace of the Chinese Communist Party. It is a monument standing in the center of a large, busy commercial district, known as Xin Tian Di, surrounded by malls, stores, restaurants. Looking above, glass skyscrapers in the distance stand straight up to the sky. It is surely an important historical site, as you can tell from guards securing the exterior of the building. However, I never expected that such a place could appear right at the center of one of the most popular, crowded commercial plaza in Shanghai. Although such a location has been criticized for losing its historical authenticity, I guess I would have never known this building if I did not explore around Xin Tian Di, searching for ice cream and fragrance stores.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1754567149859.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>National Museum, birthplace of the Chinese Communism Party, Shanghai (Self, 2025)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This surprise led me to further research about a special housing type in Shanghai. The Shikumen (defined as “Stone Gate” in Mandarin) Lilong is a distinct type of architecture in Shanghai that blends Chinese and Western structural styles. Lilong houses were first constructed in the 1840s to accommodate the overflowing migrants. It is a densely connected lane-based housing compound formed by Shikumen houses. Shikumen Lilong housing intertwines urban life and community culture through its dense and interconnected layout that blends private and public space to promote social interaction in common alleys. It is a heritage architecture that shows the way of living in early Shanghai. Siwen Li, one of the largest clusters of Shikumen Lilong (now in Jingan District) sheltered 2,700 families in 700 Shikumen houses at its peak occupancy. Today under accelerating urbanization, preserving massive Shikumen Lilong as it was in the last century is unreasonable. However, their figures can still be seen across streets of modern Shanghai. The Xintiandi and Tianzifang blocks are renewed Shikumen Lilongs that now function as commercial districts that shape the modern cityscape of Shanghai. They allow Shikumen Lilong to gain more opportunities to be presented to the world and  represent an alternative approach of preserving architectural heritage, which eventually formed the cultural identity of Shanghai.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1754416710605.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Xintiandi, Shanghai (Self, 2025)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="illustrating-the-future-using-the-past">Illustrating the Future Using the Past</h2>
<p>The method of combining modernity and commercialization with historical, cultural heritage to bring a new  atmosphere to a city left a deep impression on my trip. If not because the district is now commercialized by popular stores, I would have not passed by the historic sites nor the aged traditional houses. I believe a similar perspective applies to most people. When they are hidden or blending in commercialized and modernized areas, more people would be naturally attracted, allowing these architectures to complete their mission of sharing continuous, old stories. On the old streets of Shanghai, these historical heritages are not like artifacts displayed in a museum, but rather, their essence as architecture–to serve for the livelihood of citizens–was preserved by an operation that blended them with the modern city. Eventually, preserving the past allowed Shanghai to build its very own unique city image both in the present and the future while developing a stronger connection between inhabitants and the city.<br>
Architecture preservation is not about simply protecting the structure from windsweep and sunburn. In fact, heavy protection can trap the essence of art. As we try to keep the stories of the past in the present and take them to the future, we sometimes forget that buildings are preserved so they can serve our future, but not to make our future about working for the buildings, keeping the past as it is. The ultimate goal of preservation is to pursue a better life, shape a better future.</p>
<h2 id="hope-you-enjoyed-reading">Hope you Enjoyed Reading...</h2>
<p>And above here is the first article for my new series: <strong>&quot;City Exploration.</strong>&quot; Unlike previous articles, a lot of the ideas discussed here are my <strong>subjective thoughts</strong>, therefore, <strong>contents may not be entirely accurate</strong>. In fact, I consider this more like a travelogue. Recently, I try to think and reflect on my observations during my travels. Writing this travelogue sparked so many inspirations and questions: How do Shanghai residents think about the preserved architectures? Did architecture preservation benefit the community economically? What is the difference between Shikumen Lilong and Beijing Hutong? But I guess I'll have to leave these questions for the next articles.</p>
<p>Hope you find this reading interesting and I'll try not to keep you waiting too long for the next one！</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>References</strong><br>
“2024 What Is Architectural Preservation and Its Importance?» Archova Visuals.” ARCHOVA, 6 Jan. 2024, archovavisuals.com/architectural-preservation-and-its-importance/. Accessed 26 July 2025.<br>
Lu, Yongyi, and Yanning Li. Defining Local Heritages in Preserving Modern Shanghai Architecture. 17 Sept. 2019.<br>
“Shanghai’s Lilongs: Architectural Treasures in Old Alleys.” Www.chinahighlights.com, www.chinahighlights.com/shanghai/attraction/lilongs.htm. Accessed 3 Aug. 2025.<br>
“Understanding Lilong Housing and Shikumen Architecture.” Shanghai Street Stories, 11 June 2010, shanghaistreetstories.com/?page_id=1288. Accessed 3 Aug. 2025.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Components of a Time Machine]]></title>
        <id>https://Doria325.github.io/post/components-of-a-time-machine/</id>
        <link href="https://Doria325.github.io/post/components-of-a-time-machine/">
        </link>
        <updated>2025-06-28T19:57:22.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is this spectacular place in cities, where it takes you on a journey to another spot in the world, or invites you on a time travel. If you are feeling interested in this magical journey or just simply lacking ideas on how to spend your next weekend, feel free to open your maps and plan a visit to a museum!</p>
<p>Museum is a collection of arts, culture and history. Displayed works often include historical artifacts, therefore it preserves cultural heritage and historical narratives. Some museums are also intended for educational purposes, such as natural and science museums. Museums are almost a must-see in every city I visit. As one of my favorite places, I believe they are where we can learn the most about a city and showcase a large portion of its beauty. Especially in European countries, they demonstrate their artistic commitments through museums, such as the Louvre Museum and British Museum. Museum is a depository of arts, from the inner displays to every block of construction.</p>
<h2 id="design-features">Design Features</h2>
<p>Note that museums not only serve for the people and the city, but also the artifacts, reciprocating the needs of educators, researchers and artists. The planning must consider an interesting layout for the displayed collections and a fluent circulation through spaces that enhance interaction between the exhibits and visitors, and spaces for wander and immersion. To achieve such purposes, the design of museums must follow some general guidelines (Walshaw):</p>
<h3 id="accessibility">Accessibility</h3>
<p>Museum, which welcomes visitors disregarding age and cultural background, must provide equal and proper accessibility to all. Every corner of the building should be able to accommodate any kind of visitors in the same routes, with and without disabilities. Disabled facilities must be constructed on every floor. Lifts should be paired with staircases.. The planning of the museum must comprehensively consider how it should be fairly accessible and safe to all.</p>
<h3 id="display-and-communication">Display and Communication</h3>
<p>With current advancement in technology of visualization, there are more options to be considered regarding how to foster interaction between exhibits and visitors. Most museums enforce no-touch policy, but there are numerous mediums to enhance communication between collections and visitors. These mediums may include screens, graphic displays, laser projections and speakers. They are tools that allow visitors to explore more about the topic while creating an atmosphere and immersing themselves in the artistic or historical mood. Most museums also feature theaters where visitors can delve deeper into specific subjects through educational films and presentations.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1751843079183.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>The Museum of Fine Arts, Houston (Self, The Museum of Fine Arts, 2023)</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="environment">Environment</h3>
<p>Museum collections are very sensitive to the conditions of surroundings, including humidity and temperature. For example, oil paintings should be preserved under high humidity and avoid direct sunlight. Some wax sculptures must be preserved in colder room temperature, 10-20 degree celsius. Museums must be carefully designed with proper climate conditions for both display and storage of collections to protect and preserve artifacts.</p>
<h3 id="circulation">Circulation</h3>
<p>Museums have the power to tell stories by showing the past. This means that sections of the story must be arranged in a correct order for visitors to understand.The exhibition hall of the museum must be designed in a way that allows visitors to travel to any corner and lead them to a specific route that provides the best experience. The entrance must provide a clear guidance to the location of each section as well as service spots. Signage is used for visitors to identify their priorities and what they are more inclined to see.</p>
<p>The circulation of the museum could be in linear form, where there is a clear starting point and ending point. Visitors do not pass through anywhere repetitively throughout the route. The circulation could also be in loop form, where visitors arrive back to the starting point after finishing the route. Other options also include the division of room sections based on particular themes. The planning of circulation is a decisive factor that directly impacts the experience of visitors. A successful circulation should create a step-by-step guide that leads visitors through each section of the exhibition being connected and concentrated on the whole process without feeling skippy. I often find it interesting that the planar layout would always lead me on an arranged order of exhibits based on a storyline. While I am immersed on the beauty of displayed artifacts, I am unintentionally following the route suggested by the designer. What I like about visiting museums is how they are designed in a way that allows me to only concentrate on the appreciation of arts, culture and history, where my mind escapes the reality and loses the focus on what is happening around me.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1751843321996.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Los Angeles County Museum of Arts, LA (Self, LACMA, 2025)</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="lighting">Lighting</h3>
<p>Museum lighting is an extremely complex technical work (to the extent that I might write another article focusing on it in the future). Most of the time, only artificial light is used inside the museum and on displayed artifacts. The UV of sunlights and traditional lamps can damage artifacts very quickly, therefore LED is a more ideal light source as it does not create IR and UV (Sylvania). Different kinds of materials of the exhibits also have varying sensitivity to light. Textiles, furs, old photographs, watercolors and stamps are very sensitive to light, prefer 50 lux. Stone ceramic, glass and metal are less sensitive to light, therefore can endure up to 300 lux (Sylvania).</p>
<p>The utilization of light highlights the texture, color and shape of exhibits for finer observation. For example, narrow beam accent lights sheds high illuminance, focusing the center attention of a space. Wall washing light is used to illuminate larger artworks by using wide beam lights to broadly spread across a wall. This kind of lighting often comes with larger exhibits, which light covers on the entire surface, ensuring all details are visible. Wall washing light also makes the room more spacious. With uniform distribution, the room will also feel more spacious, open and inviting (Sylvania). This lighting eliminates contrasts between highlights and shadows, therefore offering a more complemented view of the exhibit. With numerous different types of lights intended for varying purposes, it is crucial to deliberately plan the arrangement of lights as it impacts both the protection of exhibits and the experience and mood of visitors.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1751843591650.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Dongwu Art Museum (Closed), Shanghai (Self, Dongwu Art Museum, 2023)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="highlights-and-uniqueness">Highlights and Uniqueness</h2>
<p>Internal planning is indeed the core of museum design, but we can see that a lot of thoughts are also endowed in the exterior design. The external architecture design of museums may be symbolic, reflecting the theme and mission of the museum. To exemplify, the design of the Modern Museum of Art in New York appears in a contemporary architectural design structure, with glasses as the construction material covering a large area of the building. The urban-style building expresses similar modernity vibes as the 20th–21st century collections of paintings, sculptures, and photographs displayed. On the other hand, the Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History is close to a neoclassical architecture, built with white bricks. The museum has a large, impressive central dome that dominates its silhouette. The cracks in the bricks exude a sense of nostalgic elegance. This matches the ancient fossils exhibited inside, taking visitors back to the Mesozoic era. The exterior of the museum has an essential role in creating the imaginary world and its correlating atmosphere, starting from the outside of the entrance. The appearance of the museum is a sign that informs visitors about the journey that they are about to embark on.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1754289567618.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Los Angeles County Museum of Arts, LA (Self, LACMA, 2025)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Moreover, my perception is that the structure's appearance also has a significant impact on the experience of visitors. The aesthetic appeal and thoughtful design of the building enhance the memorable and inspiring adventure through its halls. A museum is a place filled with the essence of art and history, from the interior to the exterior. Only a visually stunning and thoughtfully designed outer shell can harmonize with the expressive ambiance within.  For example, The Getty--a museum constructed on rocky hills--exemplifies how geographic environment can enliven and characterize architecture. One of the most interesting parts I had in my visit in The Getty was riding on a shuttle train that takes visitors from the entrance, located at the foot of the hills to the exhibition halls at the top of the rocky hills. Outside the windows of the train, one side is the overlook view of downtown LA and mountains wrapping around the city, and another side are the decorative plants and rocks. The way the terrain is utilized as a significant component of the museum has become one of the unique features of The Getty. In The Getty, not only the paintings and sculptures are artworks, but the architecture itself has allowed the journey of art appreciation to begin at the entrance gate of the museum.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1751844101500.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Getty, LA (Self, The Getty, 2024)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Conceiving a unique architectural design creates a focal point, a source of local pride in a community, and focuses attention on historical artifacts and artwork collections. History and arts are invaluable footprints of humanity that deserve to be showcased under a brighter spotlight. While a museum's unique design attracts visitors to appreciate its architectural beauty, it simultaneously highlights the stories within. In this way, architecture acts as a bridge that introduces the cultural, historical, and educational narratives housed inside. It invites curiosity and engagement, drawing people in not just to admire the structure itself, but to explore the rich collections and exhibits it shelters.</p>
<p>Museums transcend being merely spaces to display collections. The layout of spaces, the travel of light, and the selection of materials greatly influence the perception and interaction between visitors and exhibits. Each carefully planned component plays a crucial role in creating an atmosphere that fosters connection and communication between individuals and collections, thereby enriching our appreciation of historical and cultural heritage. Ultimately, museums serve to preserve history, art, and culture, providing an immersive experience akin to time travel. By analyzing the meticulous choices in interior design and unique architectural features, we gain insights into how space shapes our understanding and appreciation of art and history.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Space will only have a life when people enter it. So the important role architecture can play, and that space plays within that architecture, is to encourage an interaction between people, between people and the ideas being presented in the paintings and sculpture, and most importantly between people themselves.”--Tadao Ando</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>**Works Cited **<br>
Burke, Danielle. “Waxwork Wonders: Restoring and Preserving Unique Wax Sculptures.” Fine Art Restoration Company, 20 Aug. 2021, fineart-restoration.co.uk/news/wax-artwork-restoration/. Accessed 26 July 2024.<br>
“Museum Architecture: Purpose, Types, and Design.” AccessDoorsAndPanels, 2 Mar. 2022, www.accessdoorsandpanels.com/blog/museum-architecture-purpose-types-and-design/.<br>
Self, Dongwu Art Museum, 2023.<br>
Self, LACMA, 2025.<br>
Self, The Getty, 2024.<br>
Sylvania, Feilo. LIGHTING for MUSEUMS and GALLERIES. 2015.<br>
Walshaw, Emma. “An Architect’s Guide To: Museum Planning.” Journal, 7 Mar. 2022, architizer.com/blog/practice/details/architects-guide-museum-planning/.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gardens]]></title>
        <id>https://Doria325.github.io/post/gardens/</id>
        <link href="https://Doria325.github.io/post/gardens/">
        </link>
        <updated>2025-04-06T20:13:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>“When we are surrounded by nature, a feeling of comfort comes over us and our bodies become relaxed. Most of us would intuitively recognize this feeling, but until recently we haven’t had any evidence to prove it.”--Yoshigumi Miyazaki</em></p>
<p>Gardens have long been an expression of culture, philosophy and artistry in numerous countries around the globe. In Asia, gardens are especially a representation of national spirit and cultural heritage. Several gardens are considered significant historic landscape and architecture, part of the World Cultural Heritage. Chinese gardens and Japanese gardens are two popular types of gardens known for their charming and elegant designs that create a scaled-down world of nature.</p>
<p>Chinese and Japanese gardens are inspired by philosophy and religion.The use of water, plants and rocks express the infinite meaning of nature through a symbolic way while allowing adventurers to release their stress, improve concentration with the power of being surrounded by the pleasantness of nature. Both gardens demonstrate the concept of “borrowed scene,” which utilizes objects from far and near to create pleasing images from any spot on any angle of the garden and express continuity. The ultimate principles of aesthetics in the two gardens is to imitate nature and by creating landscapes in miniature. Although both types of gardens share similar elements, some characterizing features and slight differences in details shape Japanese and Chinese gardens to two distinctive styles.</p>
<h2 id="japanese-gardens">Japanese Gardens</h2>
<p>Early Japanese gardens are inspired by Chinese gardens to a very large extent. Philosophical and spiritual elements together with concepts of Buddhism and Taoism introduced from China to Japan in the 6th century formed the initial aesthetic principles of Japanese gardens.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750977697531.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Shot in Portland Japanese Garden</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Architecture in Japanese gardens emphasizes minimalism, often uses very few colors which are less vibrant, in gray tone, and focuses on presenting the natural beauty of the structure and materials. The choice of materials focus on simplicity and the natural patterns and texture. These choices are reflected on stone doors, Suikinkutsu (water basins) and lanterns. Lanterns are also regular elements which add harmony and balance to the garden. Japanese gardens may have Chashitsu (tea house), meditation halls or sitting areas but few in number and have less diverse style of appearances. These buildings are mostly built with wood due its abundance as a resource, also because of the country’s religion, Shinto, that views trees as divine, even after being cut as wood it is still a living being.</p>
<p>Water bodies are exquisitely compacted, such as small streams and ponds, focusing on presenting the sense of flow and liveliness of water. Water flows with the wind or elevation throughout the garden. Water bodies, fountains and water sounds create a calm vibe and represent renewal and continuity. This is an important element in both Japanese and Chinese gardens, but what I often found in Japanese gardens but not in Chinese gardens is the use of small streams that flow in corners throughout the garden. Japanese gardens do not emphasize the existence of water due to the geographic location of Japan as an archipelagic country and therefore have a greater focus on and fear of water. This can be seen in the use of sand and pebble stones in Karesansui formed in shapes of waves to represent water and islands.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750976585110.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Shot in Portland Japanese Garden</p>
</blockquote>
<p>While designers pay great attention to the overall look of the landscape in Chinese gardens, more efforts are spent on the details. Each placement of the object should be deliberately designed. For example, Japanese gardens often show their essence of beauty through rocks. In fact, the selection and placement of rocks and stones is a type of art often containing specific rules and meanings. For instance, one important element, Karesansui, is a type of Japanese garden style and miniature landscaping, consisting of fine sand and stones that are designed carefully in detail. The detailing of Japanese gardens is the finishing touch, and the attention paid to the smallest things, such as a branch or mosses on a stone, is extremely important. The level of detail in garden construction and the positioning of objects is especially reflected on patterns formed from stones and inconspicuous illustrations curved on rocks. Karesansui, which is a common scene in Japanese gardens, drives visitors to immersion through the art of stone placements.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750976412757.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Karensansui in Portland Japanese Garden</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Japanese gardens are very much inspired by Zen, a Japanese sect of Mahayana Buddhism. The belief of Zen is “elimination,” eliminate possessiveness, utilitarian thinking, obsession of the past and look towards ourselves to reflect our real individuality. Inspired by Zen, the overall style of Japanese gardens emphasizes simplicity, serenity, elegant and contemplation of natural landscapes.</p>
<h2 id="chinese-gardens">Chinese Gardens</h2>
<p>Chinese gardens are significant pieces of Chinese arts and culture. The purpose of gardens changes from eras, designs also evolve throughout history. Starting from the Han dynasty, gardens were typically built in abodes for emperors to rest in the beauty of natural landscapes. These gardens eventually became popular tourist attractions. Today, we can still see traditional Chinese gardens in the homes of some residents.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750977577391.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Shot in Humble Administrator's Garden, Suzhou</p>
</blockquote>
<p>One striking difference between the two types of gardens is that Chinese gardens also typically have more buildings, such as different rooms to study, read, entertainment and a diverse type of architecture, including pavilions, pagodas, gazebos, small houses to break up sections in the garden, allowing each window and angle to show a distinct view from within. The Moon Gate is also a distinctive architectural feature of Chinese gardens that we cannot see any other types of gardens. Additionally, these architectures usually are more glamorous with rich ornaments and colors. Unlike Japanese temples and tea houses that have straight and overhanging roofs, Chinese gardens tend to have eccentric sloping rooflines. In general, structures in Chinese gardens are mostly round and use mostly curved lines. For example, roofs of temples and pavilions show more sinuous variations of lines like a dragon. From a distance, it looks like a blooming vibrant flower, standing proudly with its head held high in the garden, as if everything around it is foil. On the other hand, buildings in Japanese gardens are mostly in quadrilateral form and use cleaner, straighter lines. Buildings tend to be shorter. Rather than compete for attention, they are more inclined to blend with the natural environment. Therefore, they do not have as powerful aura as Chinese architecture, but are exquisite and look more elegant.</p>
<p>Water bodies are mostly wide to emphasize vastness, therefore mostly are lakes and larger ponds. Unlike Japanese gardens, Chinese gardens tend to make water bodies more obvious for visitors, such as small falls with rockeries instead of small streams. Lakes are often the central focus in Chinese gardens. These water forms often come together with complex, exotic and bold rockeries. Rockeries in Chinese gardens look very different from exquisite stones in Japanese gardens. They are sculptured as artificial mountains from individual stones in peculiar, porous shapes and symbolize a concentration of natural energy. Stones in Chinese gardens tend to imitate the forms of mountains as well as their imposing grandeur. This choice also reflects the Chinese pursuit of Shan Shui, which is translated to “mountain and water,” referring to landscape.</p>
<p>Similar to how Japanese gardens have strict rules in the placement of rocks, Chinese garden plants have clear meaning in particular locations for placement. For example, bamboos should be planted behind the house, osmanthus should grow in front of the hall, peonies in flower beds, parasols beside the staircase, lilies and lotus bloom in ponds.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750977500366.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Shot in Lion Grove Garden, Suzhou</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chinese gardens aim to express gloriousness. Designers consider how the placement of each object, far and close, creates beauty from any angle the viewer stands from. Composition of objects should reveal closer to reality, for example, creating similar appearances as falls and mountains in nature. Chinese gardens aim to create harmonious and aesthetic compositions from anywhere in the garden, therefore designers pay great attention to the overall look of the landscape.</p>
<h2 id="reflection-of-culture">Reflection of Culture</h2>
<p>Garden is an individual’s interpretation towards nature. Due to differences in philosophy and religion, Chinese and Japanese gardens express varying emotions and meanings. The Chinese national aesthetics pursues the variety of architecture and livelihood, while Japanese aesthetics emphasizes wither and silence. Such differences shaped one to captivating one and another to a simpler and exquisite one. As the famous garden designer Chen, Cong Zhou said, <em>&quot;Chinese gardens reveal nature within the artificial, while Japanese gardens reveal the artificial within nature.&quot;</em> The highlights of Chinese gardens is how natural sceneries, their essence and beauty are shown through the imitations of mountains and lakes. On the other hand, Japanese gardens convey the beauty of nature through the attention of artificial details and carefully planned designs. Gardens, showing differences in how seemingly insignificant details are depicted creates dissimilar vibes, reflecting the uniqueness of nations and cultures.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Works Cited</strong><br>
Mehran, Carolyn. “Elements of a Japanese Garden.” The Blissful Gardeners, 12 May 2019, www.theblissfulgardeners.com/elements-of-a-japanese-garden/.<br>
Pang, Kelly. “Chinese Gardens: History and Famous Historic Garden in China.” China Highlights, 31 Aug. 2021, www.chinahighlights.com/travelguide/architecture/history-garden.htm.<br>
ShizenStyle. “The Main Differences between Chinese and Japanese Gardens.” ShizenStyle, 12 Mar. 2019, www.shizenstyle.com/post/the-main-differences-between-chinese-and-japanese-gardens.<br>
Wall, Yasmin. “The Art of Japanese Gardens | Stories.” The Oxfordshire Gardener, 29 Apr. 2022, theoxfordshiregardener.co.uk/art-of-japanese-gardens/#:~:text=Chinese%20gardens%20traditionally%20are%20more. Accessed 16 July 2024.<br>
Way, Simon. “All You Need to Know about Japanese Wood.” Daitool, 22 Apr. 2024, daitool.com/blogs/news/all-you-need-to-know-about-japanese-wood. Accessed 16 July 2024.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preservation or Operation?]]></title>
        <id>https://Doria325.github.io/post/preservationnn/</id>
        <link href="https://Doria325.github.io/post/preservationnn/">
        </link>
        <updated>2024-12-14T07:10:33.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-powerful-tool">A Powerful Tool</h2>
<p>In any community, parks are green spaces that offer opportunities for recreation and are powerful tools to address critical urban infrastructure, health, and environmental issues vital to the well-being of communities. From expansive national parks that showcase nature's grandeur to neighborhood parks for respite, these areas foster a sense of community involvement while preserving the natural environment.<br>
Different types of parks include urban parks, national parks, state parks, historical parks, water parks, amusement parks, town square parks, etc. Each type of park differs in its purpose of usage and way of management. For example, urban parks are located within a city or town and feature areas like sports fields, walking paths, picnic areas, and sometimes tourist spots like museums. National parks are often far from urban areas and offer a wide range of recreational activities like hiking, camping, and kayaking. These parks are large lands protected by the government for perseverance.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1751844891891.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yosamite, California (Self, Yosamite, 2023)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="green-lungs-urban-parks">“Green Lungs”- Urban Parks</h2>
<p>In urban planning, a park is the heart of a bustling city, serving as a sanctuary where nature and urban life harmoniously coexist. It has the power to enhance city growth and population health by encouraging active lifestyles and strengthening local economies through job creation. Parks also benefit the environment by controlling air pollution and reducing greenhouse gas emissions in cities. Urban parks provide public areas for hosting social events and engaging in physical activities. Their essence as public spaces intertwined with connections to nature is akin to Legos without instruction guides, offering numerous possible activities within the space.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1751844726160.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Gasworks Park, Seattle (Self, Gasworks Park, 2024)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since parks are so crucial as the 'green lungs' of cities in creating a sustainable environment, the necessity of park protection is underscored. By maintaining their cleanliness and safety, we ensure that parks continue to enliven the city. This is why, when discussing the management of parks, preservation often comes to mind. However, is preservation alone enough to keep them thriving?</p>
<h2 id="miyashita-park-and-highline-park">Miyashita Park and Highline Park</h2>
<p>Miyashita Park is a &quot;three-dimensional&quot; urban park located in Tokyo, Japan. Unlike most flatly spread urban parks, Miyashita has four floors, constructed in a long, narrow form. It is a combination of a mall, hotel, and park. Miyashita Park broke the traditional boundaries between parks and commercial facilities by creating a space where commerce and nature coexist. The four floors of the building comprise a mall providing abundant shopping and dining options. On the rooftop is the park, featuring a lawn, benches, and sports and entertainment facilities such as a rock climbing wall, volleyball court, and skateboard park. Unlike traditional parks, Miyashita Park is elevated above the busy streets of Shibuya. This integration of business and park space exemplifies how commercial value and recreational areas can coexist. Under such operation, the park has become not only a place to relax but also a commercial hub that attracts residents and tourists, eventually becoming a tourism spot.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750975818611.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>(“MIYASHITA PARK  | Urban Design / Master Plan | Projects | NIKKEN SEKKEI LTD”)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>High Line Park is an elevated trail constructed from an abandoned railway in New York. The park stretches above the city of Manhattan, covering a total length of 2.4 kilometers. Initially, the abandoned railroad was slated for removal by the New York government. However, an association named &quot;Friends of the High Line&quot; opposed the proposal and designed this park, protecting industrial cultural heritage while generating significant profit for neighboring communities. The park utilizes a unique strategy called &quot;agri-tecture&quot; (agriculture + architecture) for its paving system, allowing weeds to grow in the sidewalk fissures. Today, the High Line is a tourist destination and a public space that integrates the park area with the neighborhood, the street, and the city. Facilities include food courts, museums, markets, and playgrounds. Visitors can enjoy unique views of New York City along the green trail while experiencing art, performances, and socialization. Operating the High Line through the integration of arts, commerce, and nature demonstrates how a park can build connections between individuals and the community.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750972866695.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>High Line Park (Frasz)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Parks, as landscape architecture, play a vital role in helping people connect with the intrinsic beauty of life.<br>
<img src="https://Doria325.github.io/post-images/1750972910180.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>(Baan)</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="balancing-preservation-and-operation">Balancing Preservation and Operation</h1>
<p>Do the above cases tell us that maintenance is not as important as we thought? Certainly not; any operation strategy for parks is built on the basis of a clean and sustainable environment. But with only maintenance, parks are more like exhibits for people to appreciate. In fact, a park becomes a burden due to the need for money and labor for protection. But with operation, it is an asset that can attract more residents and tourists. Operations do not necessarily have to be complex, like how Miyashita Park and Highline Park run. It could be as simple as hosting performances, festivals, and social activities that raise interaction between individuals and the environment. These activities, which may seem insignificant, can in fact enhance involvement and belongingness in the community. Parks are not only for appreciation but also for individuals to feel the connection between themselves, the city, nature, and the world. With maintenance, we preserve their beauty. With operation, we keep them lively.</p>
<hr>
<p>Works Cited<br>
Baan, Iwan. High Line Landscape Performance Series. www.landscapeperformance.org/           case-study-briefs/high-line. Accessed 26 June 2025.<br>
Frasz, Andrew. High Line. www.nyctourism.com/attractions-tours/the-high-line/.              Accessed 26 June 2025.<br>
“MIYASHITA PARK  | Urban Design / Master Plan | Projects | NIKKEN SEKKEI LTD.” NIKKEN       SEKKEI LTD, 2020, www.nikken.co.jp/en/projects/urban_design_and_planning/             miyashita_park.html. Accessed 26 June 2025.<br>
Self, Gasworks Park, 2024.<br>
Self, Yosamite, 2023.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>